[{"question":"<p><b>In Nigeria's first republic, the prime minister was both the<\/b><\/p>","options":["Head of government and a law maker","Head of states and commander-in-chief of the armed forces","Commander-in-chief of the armed forces and party leader","Head of states and party leader"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Under the 1979 constitution, statutory allocation of revenue to the local government council is the responsibility of the<\/b><\/p>","options":["Council of state","House of Assembly","National Economic council","Federal legislature"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many political parties were registered for the last general election in Nigeria ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["48","54","25","38"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>When was the ICJ judgment between Nigeria and Cameroon delivered ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oct. 10,2002","Sept. 12, 2001","Sept. 11, 1999","Aug. 14, 2001"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which state in Nigeria has the highest number of Local Government Area ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Katsina","Bayelsa","Kano","Sokoto"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Government as an academic field of study refers to ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["subject that is studied in school","the study of the state and the people","the study of cultures","the study of an institution of the state"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ability to make other people do what you want them to do even if they would have done otherwise is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["authority","sovereignty","power","separation of power"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Presidential Villa in Nigeria is called Aso Rock while the home of the Prime Minister of Great Britain is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Capitol","White House","Don Dan House","10 Downing Street"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Nigeria House of Senate is made up of how many members?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["109","180","300","310"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Jonathan Goodluck became Executive President of the Federal Republic of Nigeria on the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6th of May 2010","5th of May 2010","10th of April 2010","6th of April 2010"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Federal Republic of Nigeria is made up of...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12 states","30 states","774 local government councils","704 local government councils"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following countries operate a system with Bicameral Legislature<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cuba","Ghana","Liberia","North Korea"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Security Council of the United Nations Organization (U.N.O) is composed of the following number of countries<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","5","7","4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A coalition government arises under the following conditions:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["one party has majority in the parliament","no party has majority in the parliament","the ruling party is defeated in the parliament","a vote of no confidence is passed on the ruling party"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Whan a bill is passed by the legislature is vetoed by the executive, the action underscores the principles of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["collective responsibility","separation of power","checks and balances","probity and accountability"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following was the Minister of Finance and Vice-Chairman of the Federal Executive Council during Yakubu Gowon's regine:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Obafemi Awolowo","Augustus Aikhomu","Adamu Ciroma","Aminu Kano"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The longest serving African President who died recently is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Patrice Lumuba","Kwame Nkuruma","Julius Nyerere","Omer Bango"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A major weakness of a unitary system of government is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["that it is run as a single entity","that the constitution can easily be amended","that opposition and cross carpeting are extremely difficult","that it encourages the domination of minority"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a presidential system of government the legislature and the executives are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["appointed at the same time to an unfixed term","appointed by the judiciary to a fixed term","elected separately to an unfixed term","elected separately to a fixed term"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The principle of separation of powers enable each arm of government to&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["carry out its constitutional functions","probe one another","moderate the scope of the constitution","overlap the function of the other"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Constitutionalism can be described as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["amendment of an existing constitution","adherence to a constitution","process of operating a constitution","process of drafting a constitution"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The electorate can remove an elected official by an act of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["consensus","plebiscite","recall","impeachment"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a legislative process, a bill is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["law passed by the legislature","motion accepted for debate","motion rejected after debate","proposal before the legislature"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The system of government whereby the central authority legislates on all matters is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["presidential","confederal","military","federal"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following are the duties of Nigerian Police EXCEPT<\/strong><\/p>","options":["maintains law and order","check misuse of government fund","control traffic","make minor laws"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Orthodox monarchical system is practiced in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigeria","Kuwait","Iran","England"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Lagos State under Senator Bola Tinubu was controlled by AD. At present it is controlled by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["PDP","ANPP","AC","APGA"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a state where there is no government ... is conspicously experienced<\/strong><\/p>","options":["peace","aristocracy","anarchy","democracy"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>In addition to the statutory functions of making laws, the legislature<\/strong><\/p>","options":["advises the judiciary","checks the executive powers","appoints civil servants","implements executive decisions"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a democratic system of government, the legislature makes law whilst the judiciary ...&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["implements the law","interprets the law","delegates the law","abrogates the law"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The term \"acephalous\" is used to describe the traditional political system of the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bini","Ibibio","Igbo","Kalahari"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these factors did not aid decolonization process?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the existence of the international court of justice","the activities of the blacks in America","the activities of the educated Nigerian elite","establishment of newspaper"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which constitution is critisied as having laid the foundation of tribalism in politics?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Macpherson constitution","Bourdillon constitution","Lyttleton constitution","Richards constitution"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The states that seeded from the Federation of Nigeria in 1967 declared themselves as belonging Republic of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Benin","Odua","Biafra","Ogoja"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Director of Public Prosecutions (DPP) was not subject to direction or control from any person or authority under the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Republican constitution","Unitary constitution","Dominion constitution","Presidential constitution"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The current chairman of the Economics and Financial Crime Commission (EFCC) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mallam El Nasir Rufai","Mr. Ogbonna Onovo","Mallam Nuhu Ribadu","Justice Emmanuel Ayoda"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria belongs to all of the following except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ECOWAS","EU","UN","OPEC"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who moved the Nigeria independence motion in 1953?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Obafemi Awolowo","Anthony Enahoro","Tafawa Balewa","Nnamdi Azikiwe"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Executive arm of Local Government does not include<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Chairman","The VIce-Chairman","The Speaker","Supervisory Councillors"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following cannot exist without the element of sovereignty?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["State","Government","Nation","Society"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Paliamentary statutes constitute in a large measure<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The preamble for most constitution","The directive principle of most constitution","The source of the Nigerian constitution","A source of most constitutions"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following was introduced by President Ibrahim Babangida's military government?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["land use decree","operation feed the nation","war against indiscipline","two party system"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first General Secretary of the O.A.U&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ide Oumara","Ezo Ekangat","Diallo Telli","Edem Kodjo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Regional self-government was granted to Eastern and Western regions in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1956","1957","1958","1959"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The name of the O.A.U was changed to A.U on the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9th of July 2002","10th of June 2001","9th of August 2003","6th of May 2000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Only one of the following is a form of decentralization<\/strong><\/p>","options":["decolonization","decontrol","devolution","delegation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a merit that is associated only with two party system?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["political education of the people","Existence of strong and formidable opposition party","provision of strong political ideology to the nation","increased political participation by the masses"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"}]